Guide to the Leo Frederick Rettger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Leo Frederick Rettger papers
1921-1942
MS 1113
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16.5
(45 boxes)
The papers contain the professional correspondence of Leo F. Rettger, a bacteriologist at Yale University and document the many research interests, academic responsibilities, and professional activities of Rettger from 1921-1942. Research interests in the areas of classification and taxonomy, bacterial nutrition and metabolism, intestinal bacteriology, anaerobic bacteria, cattle diseases, turkey diseases, and acidophilus milk are detailed. Among Rettger's major correspondents are: faculty members at colleges and universities across the United States, dairy farms and operations, scientific societies and bodies, public health organizations, veterinary officials, and scholarly journals and publishers.
Rettger, Leo F. (Leo Frederick), 1874-1954
Arrangement
The correspondence is organized in alphabetical order, and chronologically within each letter of the alphabet.
Scope and Contents
The Leo F. Rettger Papers contain the professional correspondence of Leo F. Rettger, a bacteriologist at Yale University. The Rettger Papers document the many research interests, academic responsibilities and professional activities of Rettger from 1921-1942.
The Rettger Papers detail his research interests in the areas of classification and taxonomy, bacterial nutrition and metabolism, intestinal bacteriology, anaerobic bacteria cattle diseases, turkey diseases, and acidophilus milk. Among Rettger's major correspondents are: faculty members at colleges and universities across the United States, dairy farms and operations, scientific societies and bodies, public health organizations, veterinary officials, and scholarly journals and publishers.
Biographical / Historical
Leo F. Rettger was born in Huntington, Indiana on March 17, 1874. He graduated from Indiana University (B.A., 1896; M.A., 1897) and Yale University (Ph.D., 1902). Rettger taught at Yale University from 1902-1942, and served as chairman of the Department of Bacteriology from 1928-1931 and 1933-1942. He held the title of professor emeritus from 1942 until his death in New Haven, Connecticut on January 7, 1954.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Bacteriology; Science; Bacteriologists; Rettger, Leo F. (Leo Frederick), 1874-1954; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Public Health; Yale University. School of Medicine. Dept. of Bacteriology
- Inventory
  - A, 1921-1932 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 16)
  - A, 1932 August-1942 June (Box 2, Folder 17 - 26)
  - B, 1921-1928 May (Box 3, Folder 27 - 37)
  - B, 1928 May-1934 April (Box 4, Folder 38 - 54)
  - B, 1934 May-1939 December (Box 5, Folder 55 - 66)
  - B, 1940 January-1942 June (Box 6, Folder 67 - 69)
  - C, 1921-1927 September (Box 7, Folder 70 - 81)
  - C, 1927 June-1931 October 1 (Box 8, Folder 82 - 92)
  - C, 1931 October-1942 June (Box 9, Folder 93 - 106)
  - D, 1921-1931 October 1 (Box 10, Folder 107 - 121)
  - D, 1931 October-1942 June (Box 11, Folder 122 - 137)
  - E -F, 1921-1927 September (Box 12, Folder 138 - 150)
  - E -F, 1927 June-1932 August 1 (Box 13, Folder 151 - 164)
  - E -F, 1932 August 1-1942 June (Box 14, Folder 165 - 180)
  - G, 1921-1932 February 1 (Box 15, Folder 181 - 196)
  - G, 1932 February-1938 December (Box 16, Folder 197 - 210)
  - G, 1939 January-1942 June (Box 17, Folder 211 - 215)
  - H - I - J, 1921-1928 May (Box 18, Folder 216 - 229)
  - H - I - J, 1928 May-1932 November 16 (Box 19, Folder 230 - 243)
  - H - I - J, 1932 November 17-1939 June (Box 20, Folder 244 - 256)
  - H - I - J, 1939 July-1942 June (Box 21, Folder 257 - 261)
  - K -L, 1921-1927 September (Box 22, Folder 262 - 275)
  - K -L, 1927 October (Box 23, Folder 276)
  - K -L, 1932 August-1942 June (Box 24, Folder 277 - 290)
  - M, 1921-1929 July 1 (Box 25, Folder 291 - 306)
  - M, 1929 July-1939 June (Box 26, Folder 307 - 323)
  - M, 1939 July-1942 June (Box 27, Folder 324 - 327)
  - N -O, 1921-1931 June 1 (Box 28, Folder 328 - 344)
  - N -O, 1931 June-1942 June (Box 29, Folder 345 - 354)
  - P -Q, 1921-1930 September 20 (Box 30, Folder 355 - 371)
  - P -Q, 1930 Sp 21-1942 June (Box 31, Folder 372 - 386)
  - R, 1921-1935 February (Box 32, Folder 387 - 404)
  - R, 1935 January-1942 June (Box 33, Folder 405 - 410)
  - S, 1921-1928 October (Box 34, Folder 411 - 426)
  - S, 1928 November-1933 June (Box 35, Folder 427 - 442)
  - S, 1933 June-1939 December (Box 36, Folder 443 - 456)
  - S, 1940 January-1942 June (Box 37, Folder 457 - 460)
  - T - U - V, 1921-1929 November 21 (Box 38, Folder 461 - 474)
  - T - U - V, 1929 November-1942 June (Box 39, Folder 475 - 490)
  - W, 1921 (Box 40, Folder 491 - 502)
  - W, 1928 July 2-1934 August (Box 41, Folder 503 - 518)
  - W, 1934 September-1942 June (Box 42, Folder 519 - 531)
  - Y -Z, 1921-1932 February 1 (Box 43, Folder 532 - 548)
  - Y -Z, 1932 February-1942 June (Box 44, Folder 549 - 565)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 45, Folder 566 - 568)